[MUSIC]
音乐
Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> Okay. Well, welcome to lecture 17,
好的，欢迎来到第 17 课
Stanford CS193P, winter 2015.
斯坦福 CS193p 2015
Today, our topics are Internationalization and
今天，我们的课题是国际化和
Localization.
本地化
That's making your application so
这可以让你的应用
you can ship it all around the world in different languages.
使用不同的语言在全世界进行推广
And then also, kind of a minor topic,
另外还有一个比较小的课题
settings which is a way that you can add a little bit of
设置，以一种方式添加一些
UI to the general settings application on the phone.
用户界面在手机上常规的设置
And I have demos for both of these things.
等下我会有关于这些课题的演示
All right. So let's talk about
好的，让我们开始讨论
internationalization and localization.
国际化和本地化
Those are actually two different things.
这是事实上两个不同的事物
Okay? Internationalization,
接下来，国际化
sometimes called I18N.
有时被称为 I18N
Because of 18 letters in there between I and the N.
因为这个单词在 I 和 U 之间有18个单词
That's the process of making your application localizable.
这是一种方式让你的应用本地化
And then, localization is the process of actually
然后，本地化是
translating it to another language.
翻译它成为另外一种语言的过程
So internationalization.
国际化
That's work that you do as the developer.
这些工作是你作为开发时所需要做的
Okay?
接下来
You have to take your app and do some things to it.
你应该开始你的应用并且本地化
Not a lot, but some little bit of things.
不需要很多, 但是需要一些东西
To make all the strings that you have in there be pulled
让你应用里所有的字符串
out or pullable out of there so
处于被剥离的状态
that our translator can translate all of them.
以使翻译者可以翻译它们
And then there's a little bit of formatting as well.
然后它也有一些格式
Certain things, numbers, dates,
一些东西，数字，数据
et cetera, look different in different languages so
还有其他的，看起来在不同语言不一样的
you have to be able to do that.
你们都需要注意一下的
And then localization is a process that.
本地化就是这样一个过程
A localization company usually does.
一个本地化公司经常需要做这些
Someone else does that.
有些其他的公司也会做
Someone who's fluent in both languages.
有些人精通两种语言
Maybe even someone who has a little bit of
甚至有些人会一些你应用
domain knowledge about what your application does.
所需领域的知识
So if it's a social networking app,
因此如果这是一个社交网络应用
they're familiar with other social networking apps, so
它们将类似其他社交网络应用，因此
they kind of know what various words and phrases.
他们了解多种单词与短语
Would be in a UI like that.
像这所示应用在用户界面上
And so this is kind of a two step process, and
这是一个两步过程，
so, you're always working on adding new features and
然后你将添加新的特性
internationalizing those features, and
国际化特性
the localizer is pretty much kind of always getting a dump
localizer 是一种很好的方式从你那里获得
of the latest strings from you, and
最新的字符串
they are translating them and sending back to you and
他们翻译它们并且发送回给你
you're checking to see if it looks okay in UI.
你将检查并且判断它们在用户界面上是否可行
You're going back and forth, so
你将来回做这些检查
it's an iterative process back and forth between you
重复检查的过程往返于
as the internationalizer and the localizer,
internationalizer 和 localizer 之间
which is usually some third-party company.
这个通常是一些第三方的公司
There's plenty of companies out there that do it.
有大量公司在那里做这些工作
So, let's talk about your side of it first,
因此让我们讨论你首先要做什么
the internationalization part.
国际化的部分
And there's really two places that you have strings
那有两个地方的字符串
in your code,
在你的代码里
strings meaning text that is going to appear in the UI.
字符串意味着它将在用户界面显示
One is in your storyboard.
有一个在你的 storyboard
A lot of strings in there, labels and all that stuff.
一大堆的字符串在那里，标签和大量填充物
And for storyboards, the way we do internationalization
为了 storyborads，用这个方式做国际化
there is we.
这是我们
Xcode knows how to reach in there and
Xcode 知道如何到达那里
grab all those strings and
并且抓取所有那里的字符串
pull them out in a way that you can give to a localizer.
将它们放置在你所给予的定位器上
And then we use Autolayout,
然后我们用 Autolayout
to make sure everything looks nice when these strings
去确认所有看起来良好的，当那些字符串
come back cuz these strings might be shorter or longer.
返回时，因为这些字符串可能很短或很长
And so Autolayout is an extremely important part of
Autolayout 是极其重要的部分
internationalization.
在国际化这方面
Okay. It's just one word,
当然。它只是一个词
Autolayout, but
Autolayout，但是
it encompasses a lot of the work that you have to do.
它包办了很多你不得不做的工作
Cuz you have to build your UI to be able to
因为你不得不建立你的用户界面使其
deal with these different length strings.
处理这些不同长度的字符串
So that's the first part.
这是第一部分
Now the way you get these strings out of the storyboard,
现在用这个方式你从 storyboard 这里得到这些字符串
the very first thing you need to do before you do
这是第一件你需要做的事
any internationalization is register
然后你就用国际化去注册
localizable languages.
本地化语言
Languages that you want your app to be able to ship in.
多语言，你想要你的应用发布在什么地方
Now. This isn't something you have
现在，这不是你一些你得前期做的
to do upfront and pick them all when you're done, this,
并且当你完成所有工作时也要回过来看的事
you can always add a new language along the way.
用这种方式你可以一直添加一个新的语言
But, when you add a new language it's automatically,
但是当你添加一种新語言，它自动地
the first time you add a new language it's
在你第一次添加一种新語言，它
automatically going to make your story boards, so
自动地去做你的 storyboard
that their strings can be pulled out.
因此这些字符串会被剥离出来
Okay.
好的
This is super easy to do.
这是一个超级简单的方式
You're just going to click on your project.
你将在你的项目里点击它
And when you click on your project,
当你在你的项目里点击它
you're actually gonna want the project, not the target.
你想要这个 project，不是 target
Sometimes when you click on the project in the very upper
有时当你想点击这个 project，可是有点偏左上方
left of the navigator, it's gonna be selecting the target,
就会选到 target
which is that thing that says autolayout
这是一个写着 autolayout 的东西
in the second column, the second autolayout down.
在第二列上，第二个自动布局下
So you want the top one, which is your actual project, and
所以你想的顶部这一个，你当前的项目
when you do, you're gonna have two tabs across the top,
当你开始做，你将有两个标签横穿顶部
info and build settings, you see those?
info 和 build settings，你可以看到这些
And you want to be in the info tab and
你想在这个 info 标签和
you'll see about halfway down towards the bottom there.
你将看到中间那里往下到底部的那个
It says localizations and
它是 localizations
there's actually just a list there of languages.
这个实际上是一个语言的列表
So here my app is going to be localizable into Chinese,
所以这里我的应用将的本地化翻译为
simplified and traditional.
简体和繁体
Also into French and Japanese.
也可以翻译为法语和日语
Okay. So you just keep
好的。因此你只要
hitting plus button there.
那里的加号键
It's just gonna ask what language you wanna add and
它会问你想要加什么语言然后帮你
you add them.
添加他们
Okay.
好的
Now, you're gonna see why this is important later.
现在，你之后将看到为什么这个这么重要
Now once you do this, the storyboards,
现在只要你做这个，这个 storyboards
if you look in the Navigator in your storyboard,
如果你在 storyboard 的导航条上
it's gonna show all these localizations, right?
它将显示所有的本地化信息
It's gonna have a list of all the localizations.
它将有所有的本地化信息列表
If you expand the little storyboard.
如果你扩展这些 storybard
And also if you inspect the storyboard
并且如果你检测这个 storybard
in the file inspector.
在文件检测器这里
Which is the left most tab in the utilities column there.
在实用列那里最左边的标签
If you have a storyboard inspected,
如果你有一个 storyboard 的检测器
it's gonna show you the localizations there too.
它也将向你显示本地化功能
And so that's a good way to just double check.
当然这是一个很好的方式去仔细检查
Oh yeah, yeah, I've got all the localizations for
好的好的，我将得到所有这些语言的
all these languages.
本地化信息
It's what I expect.
这就是我所期望的
Usually you don't have to manipulate.
你也不需要去操作
These two things in any way.
这两个事物任何情况
It's just there.
它就在那里
Usually you'll have it closed up.
你也可以将它关闭
You'll have the little triangle pressed
你有一个三角形按键
there by the storyboard.
在那个 storyboard 那里
You won't even see these things.
你将不会再看到这些
But that's just to show you what's happening
但是这只是当你想做这个时
when you do that.
将发生的事
So there are other strings in your app, though,
那里还有你应用的其他的字符串
besides those storyboard things.
在这里 storyboard 之间
Things in labels and stuff.
在填充物和标签这里
There are literal strings.
它们是字面上的字符串
Strings that in your code you put into the UI.
你代码里的字符串你把它们放到用户界面里
And the way you localize those is by calling this function
你本地化这些的方式是用一个
NSLocalizedString, okay?
NSLocalizedString 函数
Very, very important function.
非常非常重要的函数
Every single literal string that's ever gonna appear in UI
每一个单一的字符将会显示在用户界面
needs to be wrapped in a call to NSLocalizedString.
用这个封装的方法 NSLocalizedString
So the arguments to this thing are,
这里的参数是
the first thing is the key.
第一个是 key
Basically this is the thing that uniquely identifies this
基本上这是唯一方式去验证
string.
字符
Okay?
好的
And this is usually the thing that you want to put on screen
这个通常你想要放到屏幕上的
in the language of the developer.
开发者语言
Okay, if English is your language,
当然如果英语是你选中的语言
then this would be in English.
这将是英语
If you're, you know, developing an application in.
如果你知道的开发一个应用
Czechoslovakia and Czech is your language then this string
捷克和捷克语是你选定语言，这里的字符将会是
would be in Czech, okay?
捷克语
Or whatever, is that a language, Czech?
无论如何，那是一种语言，捷克语
I think so.
我认为
So that's what usually this is.
这就是它通常的情况
But it wouldn't necessarily be that,
但是它并不是必要的
because you might have the same word appear two places in
因为你可能想要在两个位置用相同的翻译
the UI and actually, possibly have different translations.
在这个用户界面上或事实上，可能有不同的翻译
Because they might mean slightly different things.
因为他们可能意味着些许不同
So this key might not necessarily.
因此这个 key 并不是必要的
Be that.
在那里
If it's not, then the value option, okay?
如果不是，这个值的选择，可否如此
See the third one or actually fourth one there value, that's
看这第三部分或者事实上第四部分那里的值
the thing that it will use if it can't find this thing.
那是一个它将使用如果它不能找到这个
A translator doesn't translate this key.
一个翻译者并不能翻译这些 key
Okay?
好吧
Now the table name in the bundle,
现在这个在 bundle 里的表名
that's a way of kind of organizing these localized
这是一种方式去组织这些译文
strings into groups.
字符串到这个组里
You can put them in little tables.
你可以把他们放到这些表里
The bundle thing is more for
这个 bundle 有更多的 对于
if you're localizing maybe a framework versus your app.
如果你局部化你的框架或者应用
We'll talk about those two arguments in a second here.
我们等会将讨论这两个参数
And then the last argument, comment, super important.
这个最后的参数，comment，非常重要
This is a comment that goes to the translator.
这个 comment 将会发到翻译者那里
So this tells the translator, this is the context of this.
这个将告诉翻译者，这些是内容
Now the translator when they're doing the storyboard,
现在这个翻译者当他们在 storyboard 里翻译
they see your storyboard cuz you're gonna send them your
他们查看你的 storyboard 因为你将发送他们
storyboard as well.
到 storyboard
So they're gonna see the context.
他们将看到内容
Oh, this is a label for a field, I get it.
这是 field 的标签，我所得到的
But here these strings are in your code, and so
但是这里的这些在你的代码里字符串
they have no idea where this thing's gonna pop in the UI.
他们没有办法在你的用户界面上显示
So you need to give very good comments here
因此你需要给非常好的注释
to localize, you know.
去本地化，你懂的
This is the title I'm gonna work that comes up.
这是一个我等下要将的题目
When this bad thing happens because the user did this or
当有什么坏事发生，因为用户做这些或者
whatever, so that they know what the best
任何事，因此他们知道最好的
translation of that word to put up is.
被提出的翻译
So in this localized string, you pass these arguments and
因此在这个本地化字符里，你通过这些参数
it gives you back a string,
然后它给你特定的字符
and the string it gives you back will either be,
这个它给回你的将不可或缺
if there's no translation, the value there, or
如果没有这些翻译，这个值
the key itself if there's no value.
或者这个 key 没有值
Or it's gonna be the translated string that came
或者它已经被翻译了
back from the localizer, okay?
它将回到这个 localizer
And then you're gonna use that string.
然后你就可以用这些字符
You can put it in the UI.
你可以将他们放在用户界面上
So you wanna wrap every literal string in this.
你想要包裹的每一个字符
Now most of the time, the table name and
现在大部分的时间，这个 tablename 和
bundle are defaulted.
bundle 是默认的
The table name is just gonna be Localizable.
这个表名需要本地化
Which is where mostly you put all your strings actually in
这是一个你放你所有字符串的地方
a table called localizable, and
这个表叫做 localizable
the bundle's gonna be your main bundle.
这个 bundle 将作为你主要的 bundle
That means your app, okay?
这意味着你的应用
Now we haven't talked too much about bundles, but
现在我们不能讨论太多关于 bundle，但是
when you have frameworks and other things,
当你有框架或者其他的东西时
you can have other bundles of code in your app.
你的应用可以有其他的 bundle
And they might have their own bundles of strings, but
他们可以有他们自己的字符串 bundle
I'm not gonna really talk about that.
但是我确实不打算现在讨论这个
I'm just going to say that most of the time you're
我将讲一下大部分时间你将
just gonna call this version of NSLocalizedString that
使用的 NSLocalizedString 的版本
only has the key and a comment.
这个是只有 key 和 comment
Okay?
好的
Because it's gonna use the key as the value
因为它将用这个 key 作为值
if there's no translation, and
如果他们没有翻译
you've gotta have that comment to the translator, okay?
你将得到翻译者的注释
So that 90% of the time you just skip it.
90% 的时间你将略过它
No NS localized string comma colon around your
不是 NSLocalizedString 注释你的
literal strings.
字符串
And that's it.
就酱
That's all you need to do to get all those little strings
这些所有你所需要的字符串将会被
to be translatable.
翻译
All right?
好的
Now, if you use a format string.
现在如果你使用这个组织好的字符
So this format string,
这些组织好的字符
the result is %g or the result is %d, okay?
这个结果是 %g 或者 %d
So you're using a format string.
你将用这些组织好的字符
You're gonna wanna use this string, class method called
你将想要使用这些字符
localized string with format to create a string from it.
在被称为 localizedStringWithFormat 的方法里创建字符
So it takes var args at the end for
它用 var 参数在所有
all the %ds or %gs or whatever in the string.
%d 或者 %g 末尾或者任何字符里
And you would want that format string to also be
你想组织好的字符
NS localized string.
NSLocalizedString
Okay because the words in there, the result is,
因为这个单词在那里，结果在那里
those need to be translated as well.
这些也需要被翻译
But the reason you wanna use this localizedStringWithFormat
你想要使用 LocalizedStringWithFormat 的方法的原因是
is because numbers are not always displayed the same
数字在
in different languages.
不同语言里显示不一定一样
So you wanna give the system a chance to display any %gs or
因此你想让这个系统选择显示 %g 或者
%ds properly in there.
%d 的那些
You're actually not even gonna
你完全不想
use this that much because you are gonna
使用这个因为你想
use a number formatter which I'm gonna talk about.
使用我所说的 number formatter
In a second, and the number formatter does an even more
等一下这个 number formatter 做一个
powerful job of making sure the number looks good.
很强大的事去确保数字看起来不错
If you have multiple percent things in there, %d, %g,
如果你有多个 % 的东西在那里，比如 %d，%g
a lot of them, the localizer is able to specify the order.
有很多这些，这个 localizer 将会给他们排序
Because, as you can imagine, as some languages,
因为，正如你可以想象的，一些语言
the words might come in a little different order,
这个单词将在不同的序列里出现
just because of the way phrasing works in a language.
只是因为语言的分词
And they are able to do that when they translate, so
他们将做这些当他们在翻译的时候
no worries.
没有什么好担忧的
There.
在 那里
All right. So that's strings,
当然，这些字符串
strings in your storybook, little strings in your code.
在你的 storybook 里的字符串，在你代码里的字符串
Now, let's talk about formatters.
好，让我讨论一下 formatters
So, formatters work based on a locale.
formatters 是基于本地的
So there's really two parts of what makes something
这里有两个部分使他们
localized.
本地化
One is the language, Japanese or French or whatever.
一个是语言，比如日语法语或者其他的
But the other is locale.
另外一个是位置
And the locale is where in the world you are essentially.
位置是你在这个世界上实质上的位置
So your language might be Spanish but
你的语言可能是西班牙语
maybe you're in Mexico or maybe you're in Spain or
但是你在墨西哥或者你在西班牙或者
some other part of the world that speaks Spanish.
一些其他使用西班牙语的地方
Okay.
好的
So you would have a different locale, Mexico or
因此你将有不同的位置，墨西哥
Spain, than your language which might be Spanish.
或者西班牙，然后你的语言将可能是西班牙语
Okay? So
好的
the formatters are gonna format things, numbers and
formatters 将会组织这些东西，数字
dates and stuff.
数据和材料
Currencies, based on your locale.
货币基于你的位置
Okay?
好的
And so what kind of formatters are there?
那里有哪种排版方式
Well we've already seen number formatter,
好的我们已经看过 number formatter
actually we saw it the very first day of this class.
事实上我们在很早的第一天的课上说过
Number formatter knows how to take a number and
number formatter 知道怎样排版数字
turn it into a string.
到字符里
And we didn't really worry about locale when we
我们不关心位置，当我们
used it early in the quarter.
在现在使用它的时候
It was a little advanced topic at that time.
因为现在将这个课题有点高级
But it was using the locale even though we weren't
但是它会被使用，我们不用担心它
worrying about it, it was using it.
它会被用
This number of format will also be used for
这个用来排版数字的也会用来
formatting currencies.
排版货币
Okay, your local currencies.
当然你本地的货币
And then dates is another one.
数据是另一回事
Dates are displayed myriad different ways across
日期在不同的地方有不同的
the globe.
排版
So you definitely need to use a date formatter if you're
所以你需要使用这个 date formatter 如果
gonna put any kind of date in your UI.
你将放一些日期到你的用户界面上
There's also date components formatter, so
那里也有一下日期组件的 formatter
date components are like the day of the week, the month.
日期组件就像周天，月天
Okay, those also are displayed differently across the world.
当然，这些在世界各地有不同的显示方式
And there's even kind of some fringe formatters you wouldn't
还有一下临界的 formatter 你不需要考虑的
think but you need to like byte count formatters, okay?
但是你需要知道像这种 count formatter
So if you wanna say 350 kilobytes left of 2 gigabytes.
如果你想说 350 千字节 左边的 2 千兆字节
Okay, those numbers look a little different in different
好的，那些数字看起来不一样在不同
languages.
语言里
You can't just put the number in there and
你不能只是把数字放在那
put kb after it and expect that to be kilobytes.
放 kb 在那之后和期望那个是千字节
It's not necessarily gonna be right.
它并不一定是对的
So the byte count format I can help you with that, and
因此字节计数的 formatter 我可以帮你到这
then in map kit there's the distance formatter.
然后是地图套件的排版
So you can specify here's the distance between two places
你可以特定这两个位置的距离
because that also needs to be localized.
因为它也可以定位
Health kit also has a number of things.
健康组件也有数字
Like energy, calories used.
像能量，卡路里
Those kinds of things.
这些东西
Some of those are different in different locales.
这些东西在不同位置是不一样的
So any time you're gonna put a number or
任何时间你将放一个数字或者
a date on screen, you're gonna wanna see if there's a proper
日期在屏幕上，你想看它是否
formatter to format this thing, okay?
排版合适
So how do formatters work?
所以要怎么处理这些格式
Let's look at a couple of them.
让我们看这一组
Let's look at NS Number Formatter.
让我们看 NSNumberFormatter 方法
Now NS Number Formatter.
现在是 NSNumberFormatter
A lot of API there.
有很多的 API
You're really gonna wanna check out the documentation.
你可以去查看一下文档
But I'm gonna look at the two most basic cases.
但是我想要提一下两个最基础的案例
One is just displaying a number.
一个是只显示数字
So you create an NSNumberFormatter
你创建一个 NSNumberFormatter
like we did in the calculator.
正如我们在计算器那里所做的
Then you set the style of the number.
然后你设置一下数字的类型
So for example, decimal style or currency style.
比如，十进制或者货币类型
There's also a style even spell out style that will
这个也有拼写类型
spell the number out, 3,000, T-H-R-E-E T-H-O-U-S-A-N-D,
拼写这个数字，3000， 3 千
right it'll set it out as words in the local language.
它会设置它的词作为本地语言
So there's a few styles in there.
因此那里有一些类型
Then you can set other things about the formatter,
你可以设置其他的东西关于排版
how many digits you want before and
你想有多少数字在十进制点的前后，
after the decimal point, how you want rounding to happen,
你想怎么四舍五入
all that kind of stuff.
所有这些材料
Set that all up and
设置这些所有的
then you just call formatter string from number.
然后你只是从数字这里排版这些字符
You give it the number you want and it will return to you
你给它数字，它返回你
a string that uses all those attributes that you set up and
字符，使用所有这些属性设置和适应
be proper for the locale you're in.
你的位置
Okay?
好的
So that's that way.
就是这种方式
And of course, think about the other way.
当然，可以考虑其他方式
If you're gonna ask the user for
如果你想要问用户
a number then, you better use a number formatter to parse
一个数字，你最好用数字 formatter 去解析
that number into a number from a string.
数字，从字符转为数字
And, that's because, as you know, some parts of the world,
因为你知道，世界上有些国家
the decimal separator's actually a comma.
十进制里有个逗号
So if they type three comma two,.
所以如果他们打印三逗号二
And you don't use a formatter,
然后你不想用这个排版
you're gonna look at that and say, oh.
你看着然后说，哦
They want, what do they want, three?
他们想，他们想什么，三个
Or that's just not even a valid number, right?
或者这甚至不是一个有效的数字，对不对
But if they type three comma two and they're locale is some
但是如果他们输入 3，2 而然后他们定位是一些
place where that's the way numbers are expressed,
位置，这些位置是数字表达的方式
then that's gonna give you 3.2 back out of it, okay?
然后它将给你 3.2，对不对
So displaying of parsing numbers main job event is for
显示一个解析的数字是主要的事件
number formatter.
对于这个数字解释器来说
But there's a lot more in there.
但是那里还有更多的东西
So you definitely wanna familiarize yourself with
因此你一定想要熟悉一下
that class.
这些类
On the date side.
在这个日期这一边
Okay, formatting dates, very complicated.
当然，排版好这些日期非常复杂
Okay, how we as humans represent dates,
作为人类，如何表示日期
we don't do it in a simple way, unfortunately.
不幸的是我们不能用一种简单的方式
Luckily there's some built in, pretty simple styles for
幸运的是有一些建立的简单的类型
showing numbers.
去显示数字
Short style, medium style, long style, full style.
Short 类型，medium 类型，long 类型，full 类型
And hopefully those will do what you want.
希望这有你想要的
Cuz if you can use one of those, then the way to
因为如果你用这些的其中一种
do it is you just create an NS Date Formatter,
这是一种你创建的日期格式的方式
you set the time style and the date style to be one of these
你设置这个时间类型和日期类型作为这一个的
kind of styles, and then you just get you string from date.
类型，然后你只要拿到你日期的字符
And now you'll have a string that you can put in the UI
现在你将有一个字符，你把它放到用户界面里
that will be fully localized in the local language and
这将用当地语言完全本地化
in the right locale.
在一个正确的位置
Okay?
好的
UIImage, how about images?
UIImage，图片怎么样
Because some street signs or other things like that might
因为有有些街道标志或者其他一些
look different in other language.
在其他语言看起来可能不一样的
And there's a couple of ways to do that.
这里有一系列方式去做到这一点
If you put the JPEGs or the PNGs directly in your project,
如果你放 JPEG 或者 PNG 的图片到你的项目里
in other words you don't put them in the images.xcassets
换句话说你不想把他们放到 images.xcassets
thing.
这里
Then actually those can become localizable files.
事实上这些可以变成本地文件
And you just click on them, go to the file inspector, and
你只要点击他们，进入文件检查器
say make this localizable.
把这个变成本地化
And you can have a different version for
你可以有不同的版本
every language that you want.
作为你想要的不同语言
But maybe a better way to do it is put them in your
但是可能一个很好的方式去解决就是把他们放到
xcassets.
xcassets 这里
Put all the images from all the languages.
所有语言的图片文件都放这
And give them names
给他们命名
that you can then look up using NSLocalizedString.
你可以用 NSLocalizedString 查阅
Okay? Okay.
好不好？好
And then your translators can translate the name of stop
你的 translators 可以翻译这些名称，停止标志被
sign to French stop sign, or something like that.
翻译成法语版本或者其他的语言
And then that'll be the name in the image.scs.
这些名字会在 images.xcassets 这里
And then you can use some naming convention to group
然后你可以用这些命名规范去
them, or whatever you wanna do.
组织他们或者做任何你想做的事
But that's probably a little bit better way to do it,
这可能有一点好的方式去做它
because then your translator has a little more
因为你的 translator 能够
control of it.
控制它
Now you'll have to coordinate with your translator to
现在你将不得不协调你的翻译器去
make sure you name the images in your xcassets to match what
确保你的图片名称在你的 xcassets 里匹配
they've translated them to.
他们的译文
But still a pretty straight forward way of doing that.
但是这样做仍然是一个非常直接的方式
Okay, so congratulations.
好的，祝福你
You've done all those things, right?
你将完成这些，对吧
You did the story boards, you added the languages,
你在 storyboards 处理，你添加语言
you used NS localize string, you
你使用 NSLocalizeString 方法
put the formatters in there, now your app is localizable.
你放这些组排版的在那里，现在你的应用是本地化的
And now you wanna localize it.
现在你想本地化它
'Kay, how do you do that?
好的，你想怎么做
Could not be simpler.
这可不简单
You just go to the project again,
你只是想再次到项目里
the same place that you added the languages, and
你添加语言到相同的位置
from the Editor menu, you just say Export for Localization.
从编辑菜单那里，你只是说导出本地
And it will export all the languages.
它将导出所有语言
You can actually select which ones you want,
你事实上选择那个你想要的
but it'll export all your languages in a format called
但是它将导出所有语言到
.xliff, 'kay, which is this international file format for
.xliff 文件里，好，这个是国际化文件
translators, 'kay?
这个翻译器，对吧
They have tools, translators have tools that read .xliff
他们有工具，translators 有工具去读 .xliff 文件
files and let them translate, and
让他们翻译
then they press, you know, send or whatever.
然后点击，你知道到，发送或者其他
It generates an .xliff with the translations in it.
通常一个 .xliff 文件和译文在那里
So this is kind of the,
这是一种方式
you know, industry standard communication mechanism
你懂的，工业标准与机制的通信
between developers and translators.
在开发者和翻译者之间
And so Xcode localization will generate them all.
然后 Xcode 本地化将使他们运作
And then your translator will use their tool, translate it,
然后你的翻译器将使用这些工具，翻译它
give you an .xliff file back, and you will then,
返回一个 .xliff 文件
in that same place, say Import Localizations, 'kay?
在一个相同的位置，写着 Import Localizations
You can only import one .xliff at a time.
这个时候你可以导入 .xliff 文件
A single .xliff can have multiple translations for
一个 .xliff 文件可以多个译文
multiple languages, by the way, and your translator,
针对多语言，顺便说一下，你的翻译器
if they're doing ten languages for you, they might give
如果他们将翻译 10 种语言，他们可能
you one .xliff with all the languages in there.
也就给你一个所有语言的 .xliff 文件
But anyway, you do import localizations, and
不管咋样，你导入这个文件
it will import it into your project.
它将导入它到你的项目里
And what's really cool then,
这真的很酷
is if you then change some things and export again,
如果你改变这些东西然后再次导出
all of their translations will get exported, so that you
所有这些译文将被导出
can just keep going back and forth, import, export, import,
你可以来回切换，导入，导出，导入
export, and the translators doing the opposite.
导出，translators 可以做这些对立的事
They're importing what you send, they translate it,
他们将导入你发送的，他们翻译它
they send it out.
他们再发送
When you send something new it has all the old work they did,
当你发送一些新的它却还有旧的工作未完成
becaus export keeps that.
因为它还在做导出的事
Okay?
对吧
So it's really super simple system.
这是一个真的超级简单的系统
It's totally built for
它完全建立在
that iterative process, really well designed.
迭代过程里，一个非常好的设计
This is new for iOS 8, they did a great job with this.
这是 iOS 8 的一个新特性，他们做一个非常好的工作
Okay? So it's just import,
对吧，它只是导入
export, and that's all it takes, 'kay?
导出，这就得到所有要的结果，对吧
Once you have a localization back
一旦你返回了一个 localization
you can preview it in really two different places.
你可以预览它在这两个不同的位置
One, you can preview it in Xcode, and
一处是在 Xcode
I actually showed you this earlier in the quarter.
我前一刻给你展示的
There's that little preview pane on the right and
这里右边有预览面板
you can preview it, and in the lower right hand corner of
你可以预览它，在右下角
the preview pane, it actually has all the languages that you
预览处，它有你可以翻译的
have translations for.
所有语言
You just pick it and boom,
你只要拿起来
right there in Xcode it'll show you.
它将给你演示在 Xcode 那里
Now that's only gonna show your static story board
现在那里只展示静态的 storyboard
though, it's not showing your app running.
它不会演示你应用运行的状况
You're not gonna see any of your NS localized strings
你不能看所有 NSLocalized 的字符串
in there.
在那里
You're only going to see the translations that were made to
你只能看这个译文
something in a story board.
由那个 storyboard 制作的译文
And yeah, notice there's that nice little double length
通知那个双倍长度的
pseudo language.
伪语言
That's a good way to make everything really long and
这是一个好的方式去使得每一个事物真实长度和
make sure everything's fitting.
确保每一件事都合适
Maybe there's places you're out of layout,
可能那里有那一层外面的位置
you need to make more room, something like that.
你需要更多的房间，像那些
So that's kind of a cool, it's not real language,
那种酷，它不是真实的语言
just doubles the length of every string, but
只是每个字符双倍长度，但是
it's kinda cool.
它很酷
The other way, and this is mostly the way you're gonna
另一方面，这是一种方式你将
test your app is you want to run it using the translations.
测试你的应用并使用你的译文运行它
Now, it would be a pain in the neck,
现在它将会是一个烦恼
if every time you wanted to run in Arabic
如果每一次你想运行在阿拉伯语环境下
you had to go on your device or your simulator.
你不得不继续你的设备或者你的模拟器
Go over here to, actually, here, let's put this up here,
复习一下，事实上，这里，让我们把这些放这里
and I'll show you.
然后我将给你演示
Okay, so here's my device.
好的，这是我的设备
So if I had to go to Settings and go to,
如果我进入设置然后继续
I think it's under General.
我想它在通常情况下
And then go to, where is it.
然后继续，这里
Language and region.
语言和地区
And then go over here to my iPhone language,
找一下我们的 iPhone language
go find Arabic in here.
找到阿拉伯语
If had to do that for all of the ten languages,
如果对所有十种语言做这些
I would just be going crazy doing that.
我将继续疯狂地做
So luckily, you don't have to do any of that.
幸运的是，你不得不做这些
All you have to do is create a scheme.
所有你创建 scheme
'Kay? A run scheme for
对不对，运行的 scheme
your app that sets the language.
给你的应用设置语言
So the way you create a scheme.
你创建 scheme 的方式
In the upper left hand corner of Xcode where you click run.
在 Xcode 的左下角，你点击运行的位置
Right now you only ever see it say the name of your app.
现在你只看到你应用的名称
But you can actually hold down on that, and
但是你事实上可以保有这些
there'll be a little menu, and you can say edit scheme.
这里有一些菜单，你可以编辑 scheme
And edit scheme will bring up this thing that you see there,
编辑 scheme 将带给你这些你可以看到的这些
the big window, and it's going to say what are the settings
这个大窗口,它将显示这些设置
you want when you build, when you run, when you test, when
你想的当你创建，当你运行，当你测试，当
you profile this app, when you're stack analyzing, etc.
你描述这些应用，当你分析它们等
And in the build, in the run section,
在这个建设里，在这个运行状态
there you can see that there's application language and
你可以看这些应用语言
application regions.
应用地区
So you can set those to French or maybe Spanish and Mexico,
因此你可以设置，这些法语或者可能西班牙与和墨西哥语
if you wanted a locale.
如果你想本地化
And then, it will make a new entry, okay?
然后你可以创建一个新的条目，对不对
Sorry, first of all, you duplicate an existing scheme.
对不起，首先，你可以复制这些存在的 scheme
You see that, lower left?
你看这些，左下那里
Duplicate an existing scheme.
复制一个存在的 scheme
Then you set all these things, and save it, and
然后你设置所有的这些，保存它
now you have two schemes.
现在你可以有两个 scheme
The original one, that doesn't have a language set, and
这个原始的，不能有语言设置
the duplicated one.
还有一个复制的
'Kay, that you've set the language in.
好的，你设置这个语言
Now if you wanna run in that other language,
现在如果你想运行其他语言
like French, you just hit that pop-up, pick French, hit run.
像法语，你只要点击 pop-up，点击法语，点击运行
Okay? And it's gonna run using that
对不对，它将运行
language and locale.
语言和本地化
It's really cool, fast way.
它很酷，很快
You can check ten languages really quick.
你可以检查十种语言
You add in a new feature or a new translation came back,
你添加一个新的特性或者返回新的译文
you just click run, check it out, okay.
你可以点击运行，检查它，对不对
Click run.
点击运行
Checking out, back and forth, okay?
来回检查，对吧
So that's how you preview a localization at runtime, 'kay?
那是运行时你怎样预览一个本地化方式，对不对
And I'll show that in a demo.
我将演示一个 Demo
There's also this little localization debugging switch
那个也是一点本地化测试
you see in there, and
你在那看到的
that's going to do a couple of things.
那里有一对东西
One thing is on localize strings from your story boards
一个是从你的 storyboard 取的本地化字符串
will show up in all caps in your UI, so that's nice.
显示在你的用户界面上，非常好
Also things that were not localized,
这个他们没有本地化
will spit something out on the console,
将在控制台吐出一些东西
saying this string on localized, okay?
表示这是本地化数据，对不对
So when you're getting something back from
因此当你得到一些什么
the localizer you wanna make sure they didn't make any
本地化你要确保他们没有
mistakes, although the import is gonna find mistakes,
错误，虽然导入将会找到错误
I'll show you that too in the demo.
我将再次给你演示
But if there's something else in there, you'll be able to
但是如果那里有一些其他的，你将
see it with this localization debugging on, 'kay?
看到本地化调试，对不对
And that's it, 'kay?
就这样，对不对
So all you gotta do is autolayout, get your localized
所有你做的都是用自动布局，得到你的
strings in there, use formatters properly, and
本地化字符串，使用适当美化
you'll be internationalizeable.
你就做到国际化的
And then it's just question, go hire your localizer.
还有一个问题，你要有个好的翻译工具
Back and forth with the .xliffs, all right?
来回切换 .xliffs 文件，对不对
So let me show you what this looks like.
让我给你演示一下是怎样的
Here, we're going to localize autolayout, okay?
这里，我们定位自动布局，对不对
Do you remember this app back when we were doing autolayout,
记住这个应用在你做自动布局时返回什么
looks like this?
像这些
So we're going to localize this to a number of different
我们将定位这一系列不同的
languages.
语言
And I added one feature to this, actually,
然后我将添加一些特性到这里去
which is this little guy right here Last Login.
就是这小家伙最后登录的位置
So I just made it when you log in it puts a last log in
放最后登录的日期
date in here,
在这里
because it's gonna let us talk about date formatters and
因为我们将讨论这个 date formatter
number formatters, things like that, in here.
number formatter 的问题，就像这样
But otherwise it works exactly the same as it always is.
但是另外它像它之前运作的方式运作
We type the username and password, we hit log in,
我们输入用户名和密码，我们点击登录
we can do change security and
我们可以改变安全性
it'll change this word right here.
它会在这更改一些词
And that's it.
就酱
So, what do we need to do
所以，这就是我们所需要的
if we want to make this localizable?
如果我们想要这个本地化
Well the first thing we wanna do
首先我们就要做
is go up to our project up here.
去到我们项目的这个地方
And again, you want to be careful here
然后，你将会关心这个地方
not to have the target selected,
不是这里的 target 选项
you actually want the project selected, okay.
你想是这个 project 的选项，对吧
Target, project.
Target，project
In the project selection you're gonna have info and
项目的选项里，你将有 info
build settings.
和 build settings
And, so let's create some localizations,
让我们创建本地化吧
you see it down here localizations?
你会看到下边这个 localizations
We don't have any currently, it just says English.
我们没有任何当前的语言，它只有英语
So I'm gonna create some, you know, let's do French.
我将创建一些，你知道的，让我们先用法语
That's a good one.
这个语言挺好
And it's saying here, what do you wanna make localizable?
在这里选择，你有什么想做本地化
And, yes, my storyboard, and also that launch screen, which
对的，我的 storyboard，还有这个启动画面
we really haven't [LAUGH] talked about in this class.
我们还没有在我们课堂上讨论这个呢
The launch screen, by the way,
启动画面，顺便说一下
is just this thing that pops up briefly while your app is
你的应用启动将要运行时
getting up and running.
短暂显示的东西
You've probably seen that.
你可能会看到这些
You can edit it and create, put an image there or
你编辑它创建它，放一张图片在这里
something like that.
或者其他等
But that's something you might wanna be localize both,
但是有些是你将本地化的
it has text or something on it.
它有文本或者其他的东西
So we gonna leave that.
我们将离开这里
So there's French.
这是法语
Let's do, yeah let's do Chinese.
好的，让我们试一下中文
Let's do traditional also.
试一下这个繁体中文
Let's do, I don't know.
试一下，我不知道
How about something Arabic, how about is a good one.
试一下阿拉伯语，试一下其他的怎么样
How about Japanese?
日语如何
Yeah, there's Japanese.
好的就日语吧
So I'm adding a bunch of languages here, and
我将添加一系列语言在这里
when I now go here to this Editor menu and
当你到这里去编辑菜单
say Export For Localization.
导出本地化信息
It's gonna say, where do you wanna put them?
怎么说，你想要放他们到哪里
I have a directory here called my L10N, my localization one.
我有一个目录叫做 L10N, 我有一个在这
And, I have this folder called To Localizer.
我有一个文件夹叫做 Localizer
I don't have anything in there right now.
我现在那里什么都没有
We're gonna put our auto layout stuff in here.
我们将放我们的自动布局的材料在这里
Here, you see, it's asking what languages you wanna
这里，你看到的，你想要放的
generate these .xliffs for.
.xliffs 的语言在这里
So I'm going to hit save.
我要点击保存了
And it's going to generate .xliffs,
然后它生成 .xliffs 文件
which we're going to go look at for all of these things.
这个是我们将要查看的所有的这些信息的文件
Okay? So
对不对
here's all the files that are going to my localizer.
这里的所有的文件都要放到我的本地化工具那里
I'm going to send these to my localizer so
我将发送这些到我的 localizer 那
let's look at one.
让我们看一下这一个
It really doesn't matter because nothing's been
没问题，因为还没有东西
localized yet.
被本地化
But here we go,
但是现在我们要开始做了
see storyboard, here's all this strings.
看 storyboard，这里所有的字符串
You recognize these strings?
你认识这些字符串
Company, last log in, the log in button, user name.
公司，最后的登录，登录按键，用户名
Name, password, the change security button.
名称，密码，修改安全信息按键
Those are all the strings that it extracted
这些都是它提取的字符串
from the storyboard.
从 storyboard 那里提取的
I send these off to my localizer,
我发送这些到我的本地化工具那
and they go work on them, and then we get some back.
然后他们一起运作，然后给我们返回信息
So, okay.
好的
Look, they just came back from the localizer, here they are.
看，他们只是从 localizer 里返回信息，在这里
So let's go ahead and take a look at the Japanese one.
让我们继续，看一下日语是咋样的
So here's the Japanese one right here,
这里是日语
what does this look like?
他们看起来像什么
So the localizer has put localizations for
localizer 把每一个本地化的
each of these things into this X-look.
这些东西变成这样子
Now they didn't edit it here in text edit [LAUGH],
现在他们不能在文本编辑框编辑它
they have a tool that lets them do that.
有一个工具可以编辑
And so let's go ahead and import that.
让我们做下一步，导入这些
So we go here, and
到这里
we're going to import this localization for
我们将从本地化工具这导入
Japanese from the localizer.
关于日语的本地化
Japanese.
日语
Okay.
好的
Oh, there's a problem.
有个问题
Okay, now if there's no problem, this just loads up.
好的，没有这个问题，这只是加载中
And you're good to go.
你会擅长做这些
But here there's a problem.
但是这里还是有问题
And when there's a problem it shows you in detail
当这个问题给你显示这个细节
what the problems are.
这个问题是什么
So here it says there's incoming translation for
这里有一个引进的翻译
one of the things in IB that was not done.
在 IB 这里的还没完成的
And you can see it right here, no translation.
你可以在这看到这些，没有翻译
So they didn't translate the word company.
他们不想翻译这个词 company
Now luckily, company never actually appears in our UI.
幸运的是，company 不会显示在我们的用户界面上
That's just like the little thing like where you know,
这就像小东西一个，你知道的
Madison Bumgarner, and
Madison Bumgarner
it was were old champion San Fransisco Giants.
它是旧金山巨人队的老冠军
So company always gets replaced with whatever
公司经常被其他用户的公司
the logged in user's company is.
替代
So, whew, we're okay.
好的
But you can see it's showing all the other translations.
你可以看到所有其他的翻译
And those look good, right?
这些看起来很好，对不对
So this one, this one, this one.
这一个，这一个和这一个
It's showing the translations.
它展现这些翻译
So this will only appear if you've got something where
这个将出现一下如果你得到一个位置
your translation company failed in their translation.
你翻译公司翻译出错的地方
In this case, it's okay.
在这种情况下，好的
So I'm gonna accept this and import it.
我将接受这个设定然后导入它
Okay?
对不对
Now I can actually go to my storyboard here and
现在我可以去到我的 storyboard
without even running my app I can make a second
不用运行我的应用，我可以创建第二个
window here and go down to Preview.
窗口然后预览一下
So let's preview what our main storyboard's going to
让我们预览我们主要的 storyboard
look like.
看它会是咋样
Of course, our S is cut off because,
当然，我们的 S 被切开
if you'll remember from auto layout demo,
如果你记得自动布局那个 Demo
we put that in code.
我们把那部分代码放到这了
We put a constraint for
我们添加这些约束
the aspect ratio so that's in code so that's not here.
长宽比，这个代码里没有的
So here's what it looks like in English, right down here.
这个在英语里看起来像什么
If I go up here and say,
如果我们到这里
well tell me what this looks like in Japanese,
好的告诉我在日语里它像什么
then it will use those translations for Japanese.
当日语环境下时它会用这些翻译
Now notice company is in all caps,
现在注意这个全部大写的公司
that's because that was not translated.
因为它没有被翻译
Notice that they translated the word name to be the same.
注意他们翻译的词
If we look at the Japanese translation,
如果我们看这个日语翻译
and we look at what they did for name, which is right here.
我们看这个他们对名称所做的位置
They said, oh well, there's just no word in Japanese for
他们说，好的，这个只是日语没这个词
that part of the UI so
在我们的用户界面这部分
we're just going to leave it in English.
我们只要在英语环境下保留
Okay? They have that
对不对，他们有
option to do that.
选择这么做
But you might say, I don't want that and so
但是你可以说，我不想这样
you can easily see that here.
你可以很容易看到这里
Especially with a language like Japanese.
尤其是像日语这种语言
Versus some western script language like English,
对比西方的一些语言比如说英语
you can see quickly, oh, whoa, whoops.
你可以很快地看，哦，哇哦
It's not there.
它不存在
Okay. So that's great.
好的，挺好
And if we run our app,
如果我们运行我们的应用
we could run it in Japanese as well.
我们也可以在日语环境下运行
And so let's do that.
让我们试一下这样
Let's do this edit scheme thing.
让我们编辑一下 scheme
So you see, I'm just taking this thing up here that
你看，我们只是正常地把这个东西放这
normally is always saying autolayout.
然后自动布局
And I'm gonna say Edit Scheme.
然后编辑 scheme
And when I edit its scheme, I can edit scheme for
当我们编辑这个 scheme，我可以编辑
lots of different things, building, et cetera.
很多不同的东西，building 或者其他
But I want it for running.
但是我想它运行
I wanna edit the scheme for running.
我想编辑这个运行的 scheme
And I'm gonna duplicate this scheme, okay, and
我将先复制这个 scheme，好的
I'm gonna call this my Japanese scheme right here.
我将写我的日语 scheme 在这里
And I'm gonna change the Japanese scheme so that.
我将改变这个日语的 scheme
It is Japanese.
日语
And it's, Japan here.
Japan 在这
But if we, if it wasn't there,
但是如果我们，如果它不在那
we could go look for it up here.
我们可以去这边看看
But here's Japanese.
但是这里是日语
And so now this is my locale.
现在这算我的场景
And this is my language, okay?
这是我的语言，对不对
So now, if I ever wanna run in Japanese,
现在，如果我们想在日语环境下运行
now that I have this scheme,
现在我有这个 scheme
you see that I have two schemes now.
你看我现在有两个
Now that I have this Japanese scheme, I can just hit Run
现在我有日语的 scheme，我可以点击运行
with this scheme selected and it's gonna run in Japanese.
选择 scheme，它将用日语运行
Let's go ahead and make this smaller.
让我们做下一步，让它变小
Even smaller.
更小
Okay.
好的
So here's our app in Japanese.
这是我们的应用运行在日语环境下
And maybe we type, oh, and so I'm trying to start to type.
我们输入，哦，我将尝试开始输入
Notice that in my locale it's even bringing up
注意我的场景
a Japanese keyboard.
操作这个日语键盘
I believe I can get an English keyboard here somehow.
我相信我可以用一个英语键盘
There we go.
来接下来
So, let's go madbomb and log in.
madbomb 然后登录
Here it is.
这里
Notice this is not translated at all.
注意这里没有全部被翻译
Notice this is not translated.
没有被翻译
Okay because we put those in our code.
好的因为我们放这些到我们的代码里
Those are not in our storyboard anyway.
这些没有在我们的 storyboard 里
So we're part of the ways down making this
用这个方式去
internationalizeable.
国际化
We've got our storyboard.
得到我们的 storyboard
So let's take the next step which is those strings,
让哦我们做下一步工作关于这些字符串的
like the passwords, secure password and oh,
比如密码、安全密码等
I added one other feature to this app I'll show you.
我添加一个其他的特性到这个应用里，我会给你们演示的
Try and just make this wide cuz it makes it
试着让这些广泛的因为这个使
a little bigger for you.
它更大
It's this. Is if you type a bad user name
这个。如果你输入一个错误的用户名
and password, it says, Login Error Invalid user name or
和密码，它会说，登录错误无效的用户名或
password Try Again.
密码请重试
So this also needs to be localized to Japanese.
这个也需要本地化为日语
Okay? So
对不对
we got some strings here to work on, so
我们得到一下字符串去进行下一步
let's go work on this string and that alert string.
让我们用这些字符和警告信息
You haven't seen this code in a while but
你没有看到这些代码一段时间了但是
here's what it looks like.
这就是它所示的那样
I'll show you all of the code I added, very simple.
我会给你们显示所有的我添加的代码，非常简单
I just added this which is doing that last log in thing
我只是添加这些，这些最后登录的
and I added this.
我添加的
If the logged in user couldn't be found
如果登录用户找不到
then I'm gonna put up an alert.
我就会放一个警告
Okay. Now that you know what
好的，现在你知道的
alerts are.
会有警告
You didn't know what alerts were at the time that
你不知道这个时候警告是怎样的
we wrote this, so I can put it in.
我们写的，我放在那的
But, now, you certainly do.
但是，现在你可以知道
Okay?
对不对
And then, here's where we do that secured password thing.
然后，这里是我们操作安全密码的位置
This has not changed, from our last demo.
这么没变，和之前的 Demo 一样
So let's fix this one first.
让我们修复这个先
This is a pretty simple thing.
这算一个很简单的东西
We got these two literal strings here, and
我们得到两个字面上的字符串
we need them to be localizable.
我们需要他们本地化
So I'm just going to create a little local here,
因此我将创建一个小的本地化的
which I'm going to use NS localized string for, and
我将用 NSLocalizedString 方法
you can see here's that long version of it.
你可以看到这里一个长的译文
And first let's do password.
首先让我们开始做密码的翻译
So I'm just going to take my literal string and
我将把这个字面上的字符
plop it right in here.
放那
I don't need the table or bundle or value.
我不需要表格或者 bundle 或者值
Okay?
对不对
And this is going to be a comment to the localizer, this
这个将是翻译器的 comment
is something like, this is a prompt for the users password
像这样，prompt for the users password
when it is not secure i.e.
when it is not secure (i.e.
plain text.
plain text)
Okay, so I'm trying to give the localizer as much
好的，现在我将尝试给一个本地化的内容
context there, as I can.
在这里，正如我可以的
May, I might even put a much longer comment, there.
可能我会放一个很长的 comment 在那里
You really can't go wrong with nice long comments.
你不能弄错用这个长的 comment
And then, the secure password.
然后，安全密码
We will just do another NS localized string, here.
我们做这些用 NSLocalizedString 方法
We'll take this secured password thing out of here,
我们把这个安全密码从这里
put it here.
剪切到这里
Get rid of all this.
做完这些
And we'll say, a Prompt for.
写 a Prompt for
An obscured (not plain text) password.
An obscured (not plain text) password
Okay?
对不对
So that's it. So now,
就酱
these two locals here are just strings.
这里的本地化只是字符串
If we look at their type, they're just a string.
如果我们看他们的输入，他们只是字符
But they've had a chance to be localized by a translator.
但是他们有机会通过翻译进行本地化
So now I can say, if it's secure,
所以现在我说，如果它是安全的
return the secured password.
返回安全密码
If it's not secure, then do the password.
如果它不安全，那就用密码
Okay, simple as that.
好的，很简单
And, you can put these things right in line, right here,
你可以放这些东西在这
if you want.
如果你想
Okay?
对不对
We could have even put this, obviously,
显然我们甚至可以放这里
right here without even having this local, or I guess,
这里不用本地，我猜
this right here, without having this local, but
在这里，不用本地
it's kind of nicer to put them in here.
但是它好多放这里
It starts getting a little hard to read
开始有点难去理解
if we had all that stuff here, a humongous line of code.
如果文明有所有的这些材料，大量代码
But, it's perfectly legal.
但是，它是完全合法的
One thing about these localized strings,
有一件事这些本地字符串
these do need to be literals, okay?
这些确实需要是常量，对不对
This and this, they need to be literals.
这个，这个，他们需要是常量
They can't be themselves variables, okay?
他们不能是变量
Because, obviously,
因为，显然
the code is being scanned to extract this out of here.
代码被扫描，提取出去
All right?
好
How about our alert down here?
我们的警告怎么样了
Well, I'm gonna do this a little differently.
我要做一点小小的不同
I'm going to put the strings into a little constant,
我将放这些字符串到那个 constants
okay, a struct that's kind of like constants.
好的，这个结构像 constants
So, I have my struct alert strings.
因此我有我的结构 AlertStrings
Actually, I have a little struct inside of it called
事实上，我有一个结构在这里叫
the alert strings for
AlertStrings
the login error alert, cuz I might have multiple alerts.
给登录错误警告，因为我想有多个警告
And, so then I have a localized string for
然后我有 NSLocalizedString
the title of the alert, a localized string for
警告的标题，警告的信息里的 NSLocalizedString
the message in the alert, and a localized string for
警告的取消按键的
the dismiss button of the alert, right?
NSLocalizedString，对不对
Login error, invalid username, try again.
登录错误，无效的用户名，重试
And again, I've put nice, long description here, so that
然后我放这个放好了，这里详细的描述
the translator can figure out what the context of this is.
翻译器可以计算出文本的内容
And then down here, I need to replace these literal
然后放置在这，我需要替换这些文字
strings with the things from my struct.
根据我的结构上的东西
So this is the title, this is the message right here.
这是标题，这是信息
Strings.loginerror.message.
AlertStrings.loginerror.message
And here is our dismiss button.
这是我们的取消按键
Okay, so I replace that.
好的，我替换它
Okay? So now,
好的，现在
I basically got all my strings, except for
我得到所有我的字符串，除了
this last login thing,
最后登录的那个
which we're gonna do in a second here.
我将等下去处理
I pulled all my strings out into NSLocalizedString.
我放所有我的字符串到 NSLocalizedString
I don't have any other literal strings other than this
我没有其他文本信息
in my app that appear in the UI.
这些在我应用里的是出现在用户界面上
So, again, I'm gonna go back to my project, right here.
我将再次回到我的项目，这里
And, this time I'm going to send
这时候我要再次发送它们
out to my localizers again.
我的 localizers 目录
Now, this time when I send out,
现在这个时候当我发过去
so this is going to the localizer again.
再次到这个 localizers 这里
So I'm gonna send it out, I can replace these.
我将发送它，我可以替换这些
If we look at what I sent this time to the localizer,
如果我们看这些我这时候发送到 localizers 里的
let's look at Japanese, you can see that, look,
看这个日语，你可以发现
the old things that that localizer did are in there.
旧的在这
So, that localizer hasn't lost any work.
localizer 没有全部丢失
But, down here is all the new things that we just added.
但是，所有这些新的东西我们添加的放这
Invalid username and password, login error, password.
无效的用户名和密码，登录错误，密码
And, here's my nice comments to tell them what it is.
这里是我写的注释告诉他们那是啥
So, they'll bring this up in their tool and
因此他们将用工具带这些过来
they'll translate it, okay?
然后他们将翻译它，对不对
So, you can how, what I mean by,
你可以怎样，我的意思是
if we can go back and forth and back and forth?
如果我们可以回去然后过来，然后来回
So, they translate it and it comes back.
他们翻译它然后返回
So, here we are from the translator.
这里是从翻译器过来的
We'll say we did all of our languages.
我们将翻译所有的语言
So, let's go to a different language here.
让我们去到不同的语言那里
Let's do Chinese, let's say.
到中文这里
Let's do traditional Chinese.
繁体中文这
Okay, so here's what Chinese looks like here.
这里是中文显示的地方
There's the storyboard.
这算 storyboard
And here, all the literal strings have been
还有这里，所有的文字
translated, okay?
被翻译的，对不对
So, let's import that.
让我们导入这些
So, I'm gonna go here, Import Localizations.
我将到这里，导入 Localizations
From the localizer.
从 localizer 这里
Want this one.
想这样
Traditional.
繁体的
There it is.
像这样
Again, I'll make another scheme here, okay?
我将再弄一个 scheme 在这里
This one, I'm gonna call, Chinese Traditional.
这一个，繁体中文
Let's go ahead in the Run.
在 Run 这里做下一步工作
We'll change this to Chinese.
我们要把这个改成 Chinese
And, we'll set our location to be China, our locale.
我们要设置我们的位置为 China
Okay? So, now we have one for
好的，现在我们有一个
Japan and one for China.
给日本用的，一个给中国用的
Okay?
对不对
So, let's do this and let's just run.
所以让我们做好这一步，然后运行
Okay? Gonna make this wider.
好的，让这个更宽
So, this is, here we have in Chinese now.
现在我们在中文环境下
Notice that this is working.
注意这个在工作
Notice the auto-layout is adjusting just like it did in
注意这个自动布局会使它自适应
English.
就像在英文一样
If we try to log in, we get our error right here.
如果我们尝试登录，我们在这里就会得到错误提示
Some of you probably speak Chinese, so
你们当中有的人是说中文的
hopefully these translations are good.
希望这里的翻译都不错
I take full responsibility.
我要承担全部责任
I don't know any Chinese.
我不会中文
So, I'll take responsibility if they're wrong even though
我要负责如果他们出错了
I didn't do the translations.
我又不懂得翻译
But anyway, there's that.
但是无论如何，就酱
Now if I log in, so let's log in here.
现在如果我登录，所以我们登录到这
That's MadBum.
这个 MadBum
Okay, I still don't have this thing translated, and
好的，我仍然没有翻译的这个东西
this is obviously content,
这显然是原来的内容
so that we're not going to translate Madison Bumgarner.
我们不翻译 Madison Bumgarner
Okay?
对不对
Although we could I suppose, but we're not going to.
虽然我们可以，但是我们不这么做
So, this is content just coming out of our database,
这就是从我们的数据库得到的内容
or whatever.
或者任意其他
So, this is the last thing we need to do.
这是我们需要做的最后的一件事
Now, let's look at this last login.
现在让我们看这个最后的登录
It's pretty bad.
这是非常糟糕的
Okay? This is bad even in
对不对，这个很糟
English, okay?
甚至在英语环境下，对不对
This is really ugly looking time and date.
这实在是难看的时间和日期
I want this to be much nicer.
我想这个好一点
I'm gonna have it be,
我想它要这样
last logged in certain number of days ago at this time.
last logged 显示这个时候的若干天前
Okay? 12 and
对不对，12
a half days ago at 4:15 or something like that.
4:15 半天前或者其他
So, if I do that, I need two things.
如果我这么做，我需要两个东西
I need to format that time, the time you logged in and
我需要美化一下时间，
I also need to format the number,
我也需要美化一下数字
how many days ago you logged in.
你登录了多少天
So, I'm gonna use a number formatter and
我将用 number formatter 工具和
a date formatter to make that work.
一个 date formatter 工具去做这些事
Okay? And then I'm also then gonna
好的，然后我也将
use a format string, you know, something with percent this
用这个去美化字符，你知道的，有些有百分号的
and then present that in there, to do that.
需要做这些
And, that string,
这些字符
of course, as a whole, is gonna be localizable.
当然，总的来说，都会本地化
So, a lot going on to localize this here, but
因此，很多将要在这里本地化
you're gonna see the code's not too bad to do that.
但是你将会看到做这些不会太糟糕的代码
So let's go, whoops.
好的，开始吧
Let's go back to our controller.
让我们回到我们的控制器
Here's where that nasty, offending,
这里就是令人讨厌的
non-internationalized code is right here.
没有国际化的代码
So, here, this is where I get the last login.
这里就是最后登录的位置
So this is an NS Date.
这里是 NS 数据
Right? This last login is
对不对，最后登录
an NS Date of the last time this guy logged in.
是一个 NS 数据，关于最后登录时间
And so, I don't really want this badness in here,
所以我真不希望这种不好的东西在这
so I really wanna say something like,
我想做一些事
Last Login %@ days ago at %@.
So, I'd really like to say something like that.
我想要这样做
And, you know,
你知道的
to do the format, I wanna make sure that I'm doing
为了做这样的格式，我要确保我正在做的
String.localizedStringWithFor- mat, okay?
String.localizedStringWithFormat 这个方法，对不对
So, put this format string in here.
放这些格式好的字符在这里
Okay? And, we need the arguments
好的，我们需要参数
here that correspond, so we'll call that daysAgo and time.
这里要对应的，我们称它为 daysAgo 还有 time
Those are the two arguments that are correspond to
这里是两个参数对应着
here and here.
这里和这里
But, of course, this needs to, itself, be localized.
但是，当然，这些需要的，它自己，本地化
Okay? So,
对不对
I'm gonna call this lastLoginFormatString.
我将称他们 lastLoginFormatString
And we will put here let
然后我们将让 lastLoginFormatString = NSLocalizedString
lastLoginFormatString equal NSLocalizedString.
放这里
And then, I'll put that format string in there.
然后，我将在那里格式化这个字符
Again, I don't use this.
再次声明，我不想用这个
In the comment here, we'll say something like,
在 comment 这里，我们会填这些
Reports the number of days ago and time that the user last
logged in, or something along those lines to make
logged in，或者其他确保
sure that the localizer understands what's going on.
本地化器可以理解的
Okay, so that's it.
好的，就这样
We've localized that.
我们要本地化啦
All we have to now is the daysAgo and time.
所有我们现在有的是 daysAgo 和 time
And, these are both going to be strings.
这些都是字符串
And, we're gonna get each of them by using a formatter.
我们将使用 formatter 得到每一个字符
So, let's start with the date.
所以，让我们从日期开始
So, I'm gonna create a date formatter.
我将创建一个 date formatter
NSDateFormatter, okay?
NSDateFormatter 对不对
If you just create one, no arguments or whatever.
如果你只是创建一个，没有参数或者其他
And, now we're gonna configure this date formatter to
现在我们将设置这个 date formatter
present the date.
显示日期
So, I'm gonna say,
我将要说
set the timeStyle of the thing to be kind of a short time.
设置短时间类型的 timeStyle
Okay, this is just saying when you last log in,
好的，这就是最后你登录的东西
I don't need the seconds and the time zone.
我不需要秒还有时区
I just need, basically, the time is a short time, so
我只是需要，基本上，这个时间是短时间
I'm gonna say NSDate.
我要写作 NSDate
FormatterSTyle.ShortStyle.
So you can see here's the styles.
你可以看到这里的类型
Full style.
Long style.
Medium style.
I'm gonna go short style.
我要选择 short style
Now, I only want the time.
现在我只是想要时间
I don't want the date portion at all.
我不想要日期部分
So I'm gonna say dateFormatter.dateStyle equals
然后我要写 dateFormatter.dateStyle =
NSDateFOrmatterStyle.NoStyle.
NSDateFOrmatterStyle.NoStyle
Okay, that means,
好的，这意味着
don't give me the date portion, I just want the time.
不要给我日期部分。我只要时间
Okay?
对不对
So now that I've kind of configured this date
现在我只要配置这个
formatter, I can let that time string, this thing right here
date formatter，我可以让这个时间字符，在这里的东西
that I want this percent at sign to correspond to.
我想要这个百分号与之对应
I can say dateFormatter.dateFromString.
我可以写为 dateFormatter.dateFromString
That's all right, other way around.
就酱，或者其他
StringFromDate the lastLogin.
StringFromDate(lastLogin)
Okay? And that's it.
对不对，就是这样
So I've just use the date former.
我只是使用 date formatter
Now, not only is this going to put this is a nice format for
不只是要放这个 formatter 在这里
me for English, it's also going to work in the local
他也在本地化语言里运作
language, as you're going to see.
就像你所看见的
All right.
好的
How about the number, how many days ago?
数字怎么样，多少天之前
I said I only want it to be like 3.5.
我说我只是想它看起来像 3.5
I don't want it to be logged in 3.5876 days ago.
我不想这个是 3.5876 天之前
Okay?
对不对
I could maybe just go for three days ago, but
我可以让它是 3 天之前
I'm gonna say 3 point one decimal digit just to show you
但是我想写 3 点 加十进制的数字去给你们
how to do that.
现在它是咋样的
So, let's create a number formatter.
好的，让我们创建一个 number formatter
And again, we already did this back in the calculator days.
我们已经在计算器那个课里面讲过这个东西了
So we create this number formatter.
我们创建这个 number formatter
Then we're gonna configure it, and the only thing I'm gonna
然后我们将配置它，我所写的就一个
say is that I want the maximum number of fraction digits
我想最大的小数部分的数字
to be one.
只有一个
Okay?
对不对
3.5, not 3.5267, okay, just one digit.
3.5，不是 3.5267，好的，就一个数字
Then I'm gonna let that daysAgo thing equal
然后我想让 daysAgo =
the numberFormatter.
numberFormatter
A string from number.
从数字过来的字符
And so, now I just need to take this login date and
现在我只是需要把这个登录日期
turn it into the number of days ago.
放到几天前的数字那里
Which I can do with
那个我可以处理
lastLogin.timeIntervalSince- Now.
lastLogin.timeIntervalSinceNow
Of course that's negative, okay?
当然这是负数，对不对
Cuz that's gonna be in the past.
因为这个是过去的
And we'll just divide that times 60, times 60, times 24.
我们也要它除以(60*60*24)
Which is the number of seconds in a day.
这个代表一天的秒数
Because the time intervals are seconds.
因为这个时间间隔是基于秒的
Okay?
好吧
Make sense?
讲得通
All right.
好的
What do we got here.
我们到这
Oh, exclamation point, yeah.
加一个断点
So string from number [INAUDIBLE] is an optional.
数字字符是一个 optional 类型
It returns an optional string and you might say why would
它会返回一个 optional 字符，然后你可以说
you ever do that because this argument if it's a double,
为什么要这么做因为这个参数可能是双精度类型的
it's always gonna be turned into a string.
它一直转为字符
But string from number also knows how to deal with
但是数字转为字符的也知道如果处理
things such as Booleans and
比如说布尔类型
things like that from the old objective C days.
或者其他的旧 Objective C 的类型
So that's why.
所以这就是为什么
Just so you're pretty safe to always go ahead and
你可以安全地一直往下做
unwrap the optional if that gets back if what you're
打开 optional 类型如果它返回如果你通过
passing in here is a double or an int.
这个双精度或者数字类型
Okay? Or some number.
对不对，或者一些数字
Okay? You could do if let if you're
好的，你可以这样做如果你有
a little worried about it.
一点担心这个的话
But I didn't do that.
但我不会这么做
Okay?
好的
So there we go. Now we've got the date and
我们继续。现在我们拿到这个日期
the time.
和时间
And again, like you say,
再次就像你写的哪有
localizers won't be able to change the order of these two
localizers 不会改变这两个东西的顺序
things if they're a sentence in a different language.
如果他们是一个在不同语言里的句子
Makes sense to do that.
做这个有意义
All right?
好的
Let's go back to our project again.
让我们回到我们的项目
Let's go ahead and export this.
继续导出这个
Okay?
好的
So I export this to localizer.
我导出这个到 localizer
Replace all that.
替换这里所有的
All right. We've sent them out there.
好的，我们把他们发到那里
Let's go take a quick look at what that looks like.
让我们快速看一下它变成咋样
We'll look at oh, yeah, let's look at French.
看一下，好的，让我们看一下法语
Okay, so here's French.
好的，这是法语
If we go down, here's the last log in.
向下，这里是最后登录
Notice here's the dollar one and dollar two.
注意这个 $1 和 $2
That's how they can control which one is which and so
这就是他们怎样控制这个，这个
they need to translate though, this into French.
他们需要翻译的，翻译成法语的方式
Okay? So
好的
let's go ahead and have that happen.
让我们继续看会发生什么
Okay.
好的
It happened.
它发生了
Okay. Now let's load it in.
现在加载它
Okay. Import localizations
好的，从我们的 localizer
from our localizer.
导入 localizations
Let's go ahead and let's do French.
让我们继续看这个法语
Okay?
好的
So let's edit a scheme here for French.
让我们给这个法语编辑 scheme
I always like to do the edit schemes because
我一直喜欢编辑 scheme 因为
you're always gonna come back to it.
你总是会回到这
It's not like oh, you're only ever gonna run French once.
它不像 oh，你只会运行法语一次
You're gonna run it multiple times.
你会运行它很多次
So here's French, and we'll make it in France.
这里是法语，我们把它设置为法国
Okay.
好的
So let's run.
运行一下
See if we got this right.
看我们会得到什么
Oops.
哦
All right, so this all looks like French.
好的，看起来像法语
Okay? That looks like in French.
Yeah, there's some French.
好的，这是法语
I don't know if it's right French but
我不知道它是否是准确，但是
oh, again my keyboard is French.
哦，我的键盘是法语的
So let's go ahead and bring up our keyboard so
让我们接下来打开我们的键盘
we can see that.
然后你就可以看到这样的
Okay? Yeah,
好的
we got our French keyboard here.
我们拿到了我们的法语键盘
So, I'll type it here.
我会输入点东西
Mad, madbum.
Mad，madbum
Oops.
哦
Madbum.
Madbum
How do I back up?
我要怎么回退
There we go.
就这样
[LAUGH] Madbum and here we go.
Madbum 我们开始吧
Foo. Hopefully, I typed that right,
希望我输入的是对的
but there we go.
继续
All right. So there's madbum.
好的，这是 madbum
And you can see [FOREIGN].
你可以看到 [外语]
Whatever.
不管咋样
Okay? [LAUGH] So
好的
there's the time and date and
这是时间和日期
you can see it's put a comma there.
你可以看到这个逗号
Okay? Not 10.7, but 10, 7.
好的，不是 10.7，是10，7
It's like those French have a different word for everything,
这意味着法语没个词都不一样
but they also have a different way to put the number there.
但是他们也有不同的方式把这个数字放那里
Okay? So there's French.
好的，这是法语
Now I'm gonna show you one other language which is kind
现在我将给你显示一个其他有趣的语言
of a fun, different, interesting language,
不一样的，有趣的语言
which is Arabic.
阿拉伯语
So let's go ahead and import Arabic.
让我们接下来导入阿拉伯语
Those of you who know anything about
你们谁知道语言的
languages will know why this is an interesting language.
应该知道为啥它很有趣
So let's duplicate it.
让我们复制它
Arabic.
阿拉伯语
And okay, it's Arabic.
好的，阿拉伯语
We'll have a country.
我们选一个国家
We'll have it be Egypt.
选埃及
They speak Arabic in Egypt.
他们说阿拉伯语
All those okay.
好的
So now, let's run this in Arabic.
现在让我们运行一下阿拉伯语
And, whoa, it broke my UI.
哇，它打破了我们的用户界面
Look at that, it put those things over on the right side.
看那里，它放了什么东西在右边
And, what's going on here?
怎么回事
This changed securities on the wrong side.
这个改变安全性的错误的一边
This was supposed to be over.
这被认为是结束了
So, Arabic is a right to left language, right?
因此阿拉伯语从右到左的语言，对吧
The text flows from the right hand side of the page to
文本信息从右
the left.
到左
Not from left to right.
不是从左到右
So, not only does that mean the text needs to flow right
所以不只是文本从右到左
to left, but my whole UI needs to flow right to left.
我的整个用户界面都从右到左
Okay?
对吧
So labels need to be on the right with the text going to
标签需要在右边，文本将
the left.
在左边
Same thing with these buttons.
这些按钮也是同样的道理
Okay? They need to go
好的，他们需要
for right and left.
从右到左
So, this is in here.
在这里
I have an English keyboard so
我有一个英语键盘
it's gonna be left to right typing here.
它从左到右输入
But if I had an Arabic keyboard,
但是如果我有一个阿拉伯键盘
it would be typing right to left.
它会从右到左输入
So let's go ahead and log in.
接下来登录
That's [LAUGH] this one.
就是这个
Not this one.
不是装一个
There it is.
这一个
And here's our last log in.
这里是我们最后登录时间
Whatever that is in Arabic and here's the time in Arabic.
不管那个阿拉伯语是什么，这里是阿拉伯语的时间
Okay, from right to left, so it's all right to left.
好的，从右到左，所有的都从右到左
Okay.
好的
Even this got made right to left.
甚至这个也是从右到左
Okay.
好的
And, that happened automatically.
这些都是自然发生的
Notice I didn't absolutely nothing whatsoever
注意我完全没有想这么做
in my entire storyboard to make that happen.
在我整个 storyboard 里，它自己发生的
But if we look at our constraints,
但是如果我们查看我们的约束
like we look at this constraint right here.
我们查看这里的约束
This guy.
这家伙
Let's look at his constraints.
让我们看一下他的约束
You see it's trailing space to super view.
你们看到这个 trailing space to super view
Trailing space.
Trailing space
Not right edge to super view.
不是有边缘到 super view
Trailing space.
Trailing space
Okay? So that's just
好的，那只是
saying that we wanna be attached to the trailing edge.
说我们想接近后边缘
And if we're in a right to left language,
如果我们是从右到左的语言
that means the other side.
在意味着另一方面
So, this auto layout did the right thing.
这个自动布局做正确的事
It attached this edge over to here.
它接近边缘从那里到这里
Because this is the trailing edge.
因为这是后边缘
Everyone understand that?
每个人都懂吗
Okay?
好的
So when you go and do a right to left language, probably
所以当你使用从右到左的语言，可能
when you run it's not gonna work as nice as this one was.
当你运行它，它不能很好的运作就像这个一样
I was actually very.
我实际上上非常确定
Pleased that it just worked, okay?
它只是运行了，对吧
But sometimes it'll be like oh, oops,
但是有时候它看起来，额
I made an assumption there that was also going to be
我做一个假设，它也将
left to right, something smashing into each other,
从左到右，互相交错在一起
so I really always strongly recommend doing at
因此我一直强烈推荐
least one right to left language, Hebrew or Arabic or
至少一个是从右到左的语言，希伯来语或者阿拉伯语或者
something that tests out that part of your user interface.
一些你用户界面部分的测试语言
Okay?
好吧
So that's it for localization.
这就是本地化
Pretty powerful system.
非常强大的系统
Pretty easy, really, for you.
非常简单，当然，对你们来说
Apple's made it actually quite easy for you.
苹果公司把它弄得相当简单对你们来说
For the translators, depends, sometimes it's easy for them,
对翻译者，第三方，有时候其他方面都很简单
sometimes it's a pain in the neck trying to figure out what
有时它又相当痛苦因为要试图找出
it is you're actually trying to
你事实上想要找出的
say to them about where this word appears.
在这个单词上显示的
You'll get some funny translation back sometimes
你会得到一些有趣的翻译结果
when they don't really understand
当他们不能理解
what it is you're saying.
你所说的
But these underlying system is pretty easy to
但是这些潜在的系统很容易
iterate with them.
重复他们
Okay. Any questions
对的，任何问题
about localization?
关于 localization
Okay.
好的
Let's go back to our slide.
让我们回到我们的 slide
Oops.
哦
Slides are here. All right.
Slides 在这里，好的
Okay.
好的
So, the next topic is Settings, all right?
下一个课题是设置，对吧
So the settings is a.
设置是一个
Let's go back here, and let's show this on here.
让我们回到这里，让我们在这里显示
Okay, so the settings app, every device has a settings
好的，这个设置应用，每一个设备有一个设置
app, it's this little icon right here.
应用，这个小的图标在这里
Okay? See that icon right there?
好的，看这个图标
So, I'm gonna click on that and this gives settings for
我将点开它然后它会给我整个设备的
the whole device.
设置
Okay? We were earlier,
好的，我们很快
we were looking for example, inside General so that we
我们要看到这个例子，General 里面的
could find the Language & Region and all that.
我们可以看到 Language & Region 还有别的
But there's more than General settings here.
但是不只是常规设置在这里
There's also application specific settings.
这里也有应用的特殊设置
You see them right here?
你可以在这看到
Mail, Notes, Reminders, Phone.
邮件，便签，备忘，手机
Those are settings for those apps.
这些设置对应着这些应用
Okay?
对吧
And even all the way down at the bottom here, okay?
甚至一路下来都是，对吧
There's one of our apps that has setting.
这里有我们应用之一的设置
Trax?
Trax
I don't have, remember doing a settings for Trax.
我没有印象对 Trax 做过设置
But that's because Trax used photos library,
但是那个因为 Trax 使用了相片的 library
used the Camera, etc.
使用照相机等
And so
然后
it has some settings that were automatically built into it.
它有一些设置自动建立这些
Okay?
对吧
But what we're gonna do today is add settings,
但是我们将做什么今天去添加设置
specific to our app that would have, you know, some setting,
我们应用里特殊的设置，你知道的，一些设置
that's just only our app has that setting.
那个只是我们应用有这个设置
How do we put the UI in this
我们怎样放这个用户界面到这里
general settings app right here?
常规设置应用这里
Okay?
好的
So in the slide here you can see some examples of some app
在 slide 这里，你可以看到一些应用设置的例子
settings, Maps and Safari have lots of settings, et cetera.
地图还有 Safari 有很多设置等
You're gonna build this UI using something like
你也可以建立这个用户界面通过
Info.plist.
Info.plist 文件
okay? [LAUGH] So
好的
it's not exactly gonna build this in your storyboard.
不正是在你的 storyboard 上面搭建
Okay? Very restricted,
好的，非常多的限制
can only do a few things but you can
可以做到一些东西但是你可以
build surprisingly a lot of stuff here with switches and
建立惊人地很多东西，这些东西关于开关
sliders and text fields.
滑动还有文本输入框
But anything that's set in this UI is communicated
但是所有的设置这个用户界面的通过 NSUserDefaults
to your app via NSUserDefaults.
去与你的应用交流
Okay? So
好的
basically, this UI in the settings app is just setting
基本地，设置的用户界面只是设置
NSUserDefault in your app.
你应用的 NSUserDefault
That's what it's doing.
这就是它运作的机理
Okay?
好的
So let's look to see how it works.
让我们看看它怎么工作
You add a little settings bundle to your app.
你添加一些 Settings bundle 到你的应用里
That's how you get it to display some UI.
你怎样得到它然后显示在用户界面上
And you do that by saying New File and
你做这些通过新文件还有
you go to this place here, iOS, Resource, and
你到这个地方，iOS，资源还有
inside there you'll see, Settings Bundle.
在这里，你将看到，Settings Bundle
'Kay? You pick Settings Bundle and
好的，你打开 Settings Bundle
you're gonna get a sample Settings Bundle.
你将得到一个简单的 Settings Bundle
This is the best thing, for
这是最好的东西，对于
something that's barely supported it seems like,
有些东西，它勉强可以支持
in some ways, this was the best thing they did.
在一些方式里，这是它做的最好的东西
Is they just gave you a sample one, okay?
它只是给你一个例子，对吧
And the sample one, at least as of this lecture, that they
然后这个例子，至少在这个课程里，他们
give you has a little grouping there with the text field.
给了你一些组包含文本域的
A little switch, and a slider.
一个开关，还有滑动器
And if you open up the, inside the settings bundle
如果你打开它，进入到 settings bundle
there's this little file in there called, root.plist,
这里有个文件叫做 root.plist,
as you'll see.
你看到的
And it's just a bunch of property list and
这是一系列属性列表
that's describing what's in there.
描述那里有什么的
So, let's look at this thing on the right, the UI, and
让我们看一下右边这些东西，用户界面
what's corresponding on the left.
左边所对应的东西
So look at on the left where it says Item 0 Group
看一下左边这里，它上面写着
at the top.
Item 0 Group
See that's making that little group.
看这是什么创建这些组的
The gray group thing.
灰色的组
It's just basically a static table view.
它只是基本的静态表格视图
And, that is basically causing a static table view
这是基本的要创建的静态表视图
section to be created.
部分
And, that's the title of it, Group.
这里有个标题
And then, see item 1, Text field, name?
然后看这个条目 1，文本域，名称
That's got
这个得到
things that describe what that text field is.
这个关于文本域是什么的东西
It's not just the title of the text field, which is name.
它不只是文本域的标题，它还是名称
But it's also things like, what's the default value, and
但是它也有东西像这样，默认值
what kind of keyboard should I bring up, a URL keyboard, or,
我会打开的哪种键盘，URL 键盘或者
you know, just a normal alphabetic keyboard,
你知道的，只是一个普通的字母键盘
or whatever.
或者其他
Then you see item two, toggle switch, all right?
然后你看看这个 item 2，开关，对吧
It's got the toggle switch there.
这里有个开关
Item three, is the slider, you've got the slider.
item 3 是一个滑动器，你会得到这个滑动器
Slider very limited.
滑动范围非常有限
You can specify an image on the left, and
你可以滑动到左边
an image on the right.
也可以滑动到右边
Okay? That's the only thing you
好的，这只是一种
can kind of customize about the slider.
你可以自定义的滑动器
So if you add a minimum,
如果你添加最小值
maximum value you have to do it with images.
最大值
It is localizable.
当然它是本地化的
I'll talk about that in a second.
我马上会讲这一个
And if you lookin all of them see number one, two and three,
如果你查看所有的数字1，2，3
they have a line there, identifier.
它们有一条线，标识符
You see in item one it's called name preference.
你看在 item 1 这里，它叫做 Name Preference
In item two it's called Enable Preference
在 item 2， 它叫做 Enabled Preference
in line three is called Slider Preference.
在 item 3，它叫做 Slider Preference
That is the name of the NSUserDefault
这是 NSUserDefault 的名称
that this is going to be set to, okay?
这个将要被设置，对吧
So every time that slider moves it's going to update
每次滑动器移动，它就会更新
the slider under bar preference NSUserDefault in
应用里在 bar preference 下面的这个滑动器
this app, okay?
对吧
So, pretty straight forward and simple actually.
简单粗暴
Localization is a pain in the neck for settings.
本地化对设置来说是个难题
Okay? Because
对吧，因为
the X lift stuff doesn't work with it.
X lift 这个东西不能很好的工作
You have to do it all manually.
你不得不手动去做这个事
You essentially create these directories inside the setting
你需要在 setting bunlde 里创建三个目录
bundle called a two letter code for the language, .lproj.
叫做面向语言的两个字母代码 .lproj 文件
And inside there you're gonna put a strings file for
在这里面你将放字符串文件
each page of your settings UI.
到每一个你的设置界面里
Now in the previous one, we just saw one page.
在预览这里，我们只是看到一个页面
But it's actually possible to click and
但是事实上它可能去点击
transition into another page of settings, okay?
去翻译设置的其他页面，对吧
You see this in a lot of settings.
你可以看到这个在很多设置里面
That's where they're kind of going down multiple levels.
那个多层级的
So you can do that.
你可以看到这样
And so for every level you've gotta have a strings file.
对于每一个层级，你可以看到一个字符串文件
The strings file looks like this.
这个字符串文件看起来像这样
And you have to send these off to your translator and
你应该发送这些到你的 translator 那里
they have to translate them as well,
他们也会翻译好它
in addition to the x-lifts.
添加一个 x-lifts 文件
So this is a pain.
只是一个难题
I'm sure Apple eventually will
我确定 Apple 最终会
integrate into the x-lifts system.
集成到 x-lifts 系统里去
However, it's a little bit showing you that settings is
然而，显示给你们看的设置
not a primary user interface for your app.
并不是你们应用的主要用户界面
You really wanna use it sparingly.
你真的应当谨慎使用
You don't want people to have to go to Settings unless
你不想别人使用设置除非
you know, there's setting something that's really gonna
你知道，有些设置只设置
be set once and maybe never changed again.
一次，可能再也不会改变
Okay?
好的
Or, something that they set and then,
有些东西被设置了
it only changes in the future because something big happens.
在未来它只会改变因为发生什么大件事
Like, in mail, you set your accounts up once.
就像你的邮件，你设置帐号一次
And they only change if you decide
它们只有当你不想
not to use that email account or you change your password.
使用这个帐号或者你改变密码的时候需要设置
Maybe you have to go back in there.
可能你还会回到这
That makes sense for
这样对于不是
that to not be in the main user interface.
主要的用户界面才有意义
It may be off in settings.
它在设置之外
Okay?
对吧
But you do not want to have the normal use of your app
但是你不想正常使用你的应用
require them to be going to settings all of the time.
都需要去设置什么
Okay? If you have a setting that
对吧，如果你设置
people are setting
别人也会不断设置
constantly you should have UI in your normal app for it.
那你就应该在正常使用应用状态下配置好它
'Kay?
对吧
This is just UI that you want to kind of get out of the way
这只是用户界面你想要从你的
of your main UI because people aren't going there very much.
主要用户界面里剥离开，因为别人不想经常去配置它
All right? So that's what
对吧，这就是
setting's about.
设置
So I'm going to do a demo with settings,
我将给你演示这个设置
but since I won't come back to the slides,
回到 slides 之前
let's talk about what's coming up here.
让我们讲一下它怎么发生
Wednesday is the alternate final as you know
周三是 alternate final，你们知道的
I need your slides today if you want to present at
如果你们想要 alternate final 演示
that alternate final.
今天你们要给我 slides
No section on Friday but your final project is due 11:59 and
周五没课，你们的 final project 的期限是 11:59:59
59 seconds on Friday night.
周五晚
Okay? Pacific time.
好的，美国西部标准时间
Saturday your slides are due by midnight.
周六半夜是你们 slides 的期限
Okay?
好的
Please make your slides 1280 by 720.
请确保你们的 slides 是 1280x720 的
Okay?
对吧
In other words widescreen format.
换句话说宽屏格式
Do not give me those 1024 by 768s or 640 [LAUGH] by 480.
不要给我 1024x768 或者 640x480
Okay?
对吧
Widescreen just like this, like you see right here
宽度就是这样，就像你们看的的这个
because it can be projected right here just like this.
因为它在这的投影刚好
Okay?
好的
I prefer Keynote.
我用 Keynote
If you can do Keynote, please do Keynote because
如果你们用 Keynote，那就用 Keynote 因为
what you see in Keynote is what I'm gonna get, and
你在 Keynote 所做的
what everyone's gonna get when I put it on screen.
这里就怎么显示
If you send me a PowerPoint,
如果你发给我 PowerPoint
Keynote is really good at opening up PowerPoints, but
Keynote 可以很好兼容 PowerPoint
if you have a weird font in there,
但是有可能会有怪异的字体问题
it might get turned into Helvetica or something.
它可能会变成 Helvetica 或其他字体
And then it's gonna looks like a mess.
然后看起来有点混乱
Okay?
好的
So if you can do Keynote, please do,
如果你用 Keynote，好好使用
I understand not everyone has a Mac with Keynote.
我理解并不是每一个人的 Mac 都有 Keynote
Totally understandable.
完全理解
So PowerPoint I will accept.
因此 PowerPoint 我也接受
But please, if you can do Keynote.
但是，如果可以请用 Keynote
And then, next week normal exam period.
然后下一周是正常的考试期间
I believe it's Thursday of finals week, 12:15 to 3:15.
最后一周的周四 12:15 到 3:15
If that's, anyone correct me if I'm wrong, but
如果这样，如果我错了，大家记得纠正我
I think that's when it is.
应该没有错吧
Then we will do the presentations.
我们那天做展示
There's so many of you,
你们这么多人
this is the largest enrollment we've ever had, so
这是历年以来最多上这个课的人
you'll only get 90 seconds each.
所以你们每个人有 90 秒
I know that sounds tight.
我知道这听起来时间很紧
If we have a lot of people going Wednesday,
如果我们周三有很多人
maybe I'll try and give you an extra ten seconds or
我可以试着给你们额外的 10 秒或者
something like that.
什么
But if you just do the math, a hundred people,
如果你们都一起上，100多号人
three hours, especially with the time to transition,
三个小时，还有交换时间
walk up and down and technical problems.
走路和技术问题
We really can't give you more than that, unfortunately.
不幸的是我们不能给你们那么多时间
Any questions before I do this last demo?
有没有问题
And then we'll be done for today.
今天我们就要结束了
Okay.
好的
So, the way I'm gonna do the Settings bundle,
这是去到我们 Settings bundle 的方式
is I'm gonna add a setting to Bouncer.
我需要设置一个 Bouncer
Remember Bouncer?
记得 Bouncer 吗
Thing bouncing, the square, bouncing around?
Thing bouncing，正方形的，活跃的
I'm going to make it so
我将要做那个
that bouncer, we can set its elasticity in settings.
bouncer，我们可以把它放在设置里
Now, elasticity,
现在，灵活性
you're probably going to be setting a lot in Bouncer.
你可能会被设置很多在 Bouncer 这里
You want to set it to the way you like Bouncer to happen and
你想要设置为你希望的方式
you're just going to leave it.
你只要离开它
Okay? So
对吧
that's what we're going to do.
我们要怎么做
So let's go back to Bouncer.
让我们回到 Bouncer
Here's Bouncer.
这是 Bouncer
That's where we left it off last time.
这是我们上次留下的
I'm gonna run Bouncer here just so
我将运行这个 Bouncer
that we can remind ourselves what it looks like.
来看看它是什么样
All right. So Bouncer,
好的，Bouncer
remember this thing just bounces off the walls.
记住这个东西只是在墙里的 Bounce
And it's pretty bouncy.
它是相当有弹性的
It's not super bouncy.
这是不是超级有弹性
But if I take it up to the top and I just let it fall down.
如果我想要它到顶部，我只要让它掉下来
You know, it bounces about half way back up, okay?
你知道的，bounce 大约有一半退减，对吧
Slowly bouncing less and less.
跳的越来越慢
And that's because we set the elasticity in Bouncer
这是因为我们设置的
over here to be 0.85.
弹性在这里是 0.85
So it's not full bouncing, okay?
这不是满弹性，对吧
It's 85% bouncing.
85% 的弹性
So it's losing energy with each collision,
所以它每次碰撞都减小能量
but not too bad.
这没什么不好
So this is the thing that we're going to have
这就是我们在这里的
set in settings.
设置
Instead of being point 85 all the time we're going to set it
替换为 85%，我们要把它设置在
in settings.
这个设置里
So let's just add a settings bundle to our app.
让我们添加一个 settings bundle
So we go new file, we go iOS resource,
一个新文件，iOS 资源
here's settings bundle right here.
这里是 settings bundle
Just double click, what do you want to call it?
只是双击，你要怎么称呼它
We'll call it settings,
我们叫它设置
that what people usually call their settings bundles.
通常人们称它为 settings bundles
And here it is, our settings bundle right here.
这就是，我们的 settings bundle
If you click on the bundle itself,
如果你在 bundle 里点击
you just get this little lego brick.
你刚刚只是得到这个小小的乐高砖
But if you go down here to root.plist, you will see
如果你到这个 root.plist 文件这里，你会看到
here is that default one I was showing you in the slide,
这里的默认设置，我在 slide 会给你们展示的
that it gives you.
这里直接就有
And here is the strings that go along with this plist.
这里就是这个 plist 文件的字符
This is what you would send off to your localizer right
这是你将要发送给你的 localizer
here for this particular plist file.
特殊 plist 文件
So we're gonna Run just to see this UI, which has got
我们将要运行它，看这个用户界面
a group with a text field and a toggle switch and a slider.
一组文本框还有一个开关和滑动器
We're gonna see that in our Settings app.
我们来看我们的设置应用
So let's just Run.
让它运行
Now, every time you Run, it installs the Settings
现在每一次你运行它，它安装这个 Settings bundle
bundle into your system.
到你的系统里
So here we go.
看下一个
We have this thing, it's 0.85, so let's go over to settings.
我们有这个东西，它是 0.85，让我们回到设置
Actually, let's make our slide a little easier here,
事实上，让我们的 slide 简单一点
a little less swapping around.
少互相交换
Let's put Bouncer on this page.
放这个 bouncer 到这个页面
Okay? So let's go to settings and
去到设置上
now, when we go down to settings, see we got Bouncer.
现在，当我们回到设置这里，看我们的 Bouncer
Okay, it added things for bouncer and
好的，它为 bouncer 添加了什么
if we click on Bouncer.
如果我们点击 bouncer
There it is.
像这样
That name field right here.
在这个文本输入框这里
And Enabled in this slider.
激活这个滑动器
Okay? So that's a good start.
这是很好的开始
Now, let's change this UI right here to be what we want,
让我们改变这个用户界面，让它变成我们想要的样子
which is we just really want a slider for elasticity.
我们只是想这个滑动器对应弹性
I'm going to keep this group at the top, but instead of
我将把这一组放在顶部
calling it group, I'm going to call it Elasticity.
把这个组的名称替换为弹性
Elasticity, okay?
弹性，好的
And I don't need a text field.
我不想要这个文本框
We're not typing a text field.
我们不用输入到文本框里
So you can delete things by just hitting
你们可以删除这个东西通过
Backspace to delete.
点击 Backspace 这个键
Same thing, toggle switch.
同理，开关
Delete, I don't want that.
删掉，我不想要这个
But I do want the slider.
但是我想要这个滑动器
I'm gonna have the default value be the 0.85
我想要这个默认值是 0.85
that we have now.
我们所知道的
Let's say the maximum is about 1.1.
让我们写这个最大值 1.1
If we start getting to more than 1.1,
如果我们超过 1.1
in other words when it bounces off it gains energy,
换句话说，这个 bounce 一直获得能量
that thing is going to be ripping around so fast.
它会越来越快
So that's the maximum we want to allow.
所以这是我们想要的最大值
The minimum, we don't really want zero,
最小值，我不想是 0
that would be just death.
因为那样它直接就死掉了
So let's make it like 0.5, which is pretty dampened.
所以让我们设置为 0.5，衰减型
But not complete death when it hits something, okay?
它不会一碰到东西就停止
And then I don't really like this as my NS user default
我不想这个作为我的 NS 用户默认
name.
名称
I'm gonna call it, how about BouncerBehavior, since that's
我想要叫它，BouncerBehavior 怎么样
the class that we're gonna be setting this in, .Elasticity.
正好把它作为 class 名称，.Elasticity
Okay? It's kind of decent name.
好的，就这个相当好的名称
Okay? Comma name spaced name.
好的，停顿名称空格名称
So now, we're gonna get a slider
现在，我们将得到滑动器
with elasticity as the name of the group.
它有一个组叫作弹性
So let's take a look at that.
让我们看一下这个
All right. So we go
好的
back here to Settings.
回到设置
And we look at Bouncer.
我们看这个 Bouncer
Here it is. Elasticity.
这里，弹性
And we've got this on sliders.
我们会在滑动器得到这个
Now as I move this slider, it is changing that
现在我移动这个滑动器，它改变了
ns user default from 1.1 all the way down to 0.5.
NS 用户默认值从 0.5 到 1.1
Okay? 1.1, 0.5,
好的，1.1，0.5
and everywhere in between.
在这之间
Okay?
好的
Now, it's only setting the NS user default at this point.
这只是设置 NS 用户默认值
We're not actually looking at the value.
我们没有真正看它的值
So when we go back.
当我回过去
Sorry. When we go back here to
抱歉，当我们回到这里
Bouncer, it's still bouncing along at 0.85,
Bouncer 这里，它仍然是 0.85
no matter what I set that to, okay?
无论我怎么设置这个，对吧
So now, we need to look at the NS user default and
好，现在我们需要查看 NS user default
have it change the elasticity.
还有这个改变的弹性
We can do that right here.
我们可以在这里做
Nice and wide.
好又宽
I set a 0.85.
我设置 0.85
I'm gonna say,
我将会写
NSUserDefaults.standardUserDe- faults().doubleForKey.
And, we called it Bouncer.
我们称它为 Bouncer
I should probably have a nice constant for this,
我应该可能会得到一个不变的值
but we'll type it in for speed here.
但是我们要输入它的速率
To behavior, that elasticity.
行为，弹性
Now, this is a double.
现在，这是双倍的
And elasticity here is a CGFloat.
还有弹性这里 CGFloat 类型
So we need to put that in CGFloat.
我们需要放这个到 CGFloat
Okay?
好的
And so, that's good.
相当好
So let's go ahead and now see what happens.
让我们继续看会发生什么
Okay. So
好的
it looks like we have low elasticity.
看起来我们有一个很低的弹性
See how it's barely bouncing?
看它是咋样的弹性
'Kay?
好的
And so let's go look and see what our elasticity is set to.
回过头看我们的弹性
Bouncer, we have it right in the middle.
Bouncer，我们把它放在中间
So let's set it to high elasticity.
让我们设置一个高点的弹性
And go back and see if that'll work.
回去看它运作状况
So we go up to Bouncer.
看回这个 Bouncer
And, oh. It's still low.
它仍然很慢
Well, what's going on?
怎么回事
Okay? Why didn't that pick that up?
为什么没有弹起来
That's because we only call this once when our app starts.
这是因为我们只是在应用启动时才启用这个设置
So whatever the elasticity was in the settings
所以不管它的弹性设置是什么
at the time our app launched, that's what we get.
当我们的应用运行，它就是那个弹性
And if the user goes and
如果用户回去
changes it, it makes no difference.
改变它，它不会有变化
So, how do we make it so that the user can go to settings,
所以，要怎么修改，让用户回到修改设置后
change the elasticity and come back.
会生效
And it will be different in Bouncer without quitting and
Bouncer 不需要退出
restarting Bouncer and all that stuff?
然后重启
Well, the answer to that is Notifications.
它需要的是通知
There's an NS notification you get every time your NS user
这个 NS 通知，你每次用你的
defaults change.
NS user defaults 就会改变
Okay? That's pretty cool.
很酷
So, let's go NS Notification Center, Default Center,
输入 NSNotificationCenter.defaultCenter
add Observer for name.
addObserverForName.
The name is NSUserDefaultDidChange,
这个叫 NSUserDefaultDidChange 的方法
as you might imagine.
你可以想象
okay?
The object is I don't care, anybody can send me that.
这个对象我不关心，每个人都可以发给我那个
The queue, we'll just do the main queue, and using
queue，我们就用 main queue
block this is what's gonna happen when things change.
usingBlock 有些变化
And I'm actually going to do our closing,
事实上回到我们的
trailing, closure notation here.
之前通知这里
So here's the notification, this getting passed to me,
这个 notification，通过这里
I actually don't even need to look at that.
我事实上不需要看到这个
And inside here I'm just gonna do this.
在这里我只是做这个
Okay.
好的
So every time my NSUserDefault change,
每次我们的 NSUserDefault 改变
I'm just going to update the elasticity.
我就更新这个弹性
Okay.
Now really, to be a good citizen here,
作为一个好公民
I should be doing, let observer equals.
我应该这样做，让这个 observer 等于
And somewhere else, I should be doing
其他什么的，我写这个
NSNotificationDefaultCenter remove observer, this thing.
NSNotificationDefaultCenter 移除 observer 这个东西
But the way our app is right now, pretty much Bouncer
但是我们应用现在这个方式，
comes up, takes over the screen and never leaves.
发生，接管屏幕还有从不离开
So it's probably okay to not be doing that here.
所以在这里它可能还没有做好
Besides, it's a demo so we're not going to do it.
此外，我们还有一个演示
But generally, when you add an observer,
通常来说，当你们添加一个观察器
you want to get that observer cookie back and
你想要得到观察器的 cookie
you want to remove it somewhere sensible.
你想要删除其他敏感信息
All right? So let's see if this works.
好的，让我们看看它怎么工作
Okay? Now,
好的现在
last time we changed the elasticity to 1.1, I think.
最后一次我们改变这个弹性为 1.1
Right. See? So look,
看
this guy's gonna go pretty wild, okay?
这家伙看起来有点野
He's gaining speed with every bounce.
它每次碰撞都获得新的速度
So let's slow him down.
所以，让它慢下来
Let's go over into Settings.
让我们回到设置
Notice that every time you install it,
注意你安装它的每一次
it's gonna install it here.
它会在这里安装
So let's change our elasticity from 1.1 down to really slow.
让我们改变这个弹性从 1.1 到实际的慢速度
Okay?
好的
Now, we can go back to Bouncer and
让我们回到 Bouncer
the next time Bouncer hits, it slows down, okay?
下一次 Bouncer 碰撞，它减速
See that? Almost dead.
看没，快要死了
Very little bounce.
非常小的弹力
Let's go back and change it again.
让我们回去再改一下
Go all the way back up to.
一路回升
Whoops.
哇
Up to high speed.
最高速度
And the next hit gaining energy.
每一次撞击都获得能量
Oh, yeah.
好的
Gaining more and more speed with every bounce.
获得越来越快的速度
Okay?
好的
There we go.
接下来
I don't even need to look.
我甚至都不需要看
Okay.
好的
[LAUGH] And it just bounced off and just disappeared.
它一直反弹然后消失了
Went into some ether.
来看一些其他的
Okay. [SOUND] That is it.
好的，就是这个
I finished early for once today, so thank you all for
我今天提早结束了，非常感谢
coming.
你们的到来
And I'll be here if you have any questions.
我会在这如果你们有什么问题
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu